This movie will blow you away.
Tornado Valley is a action, adventure, drama film directed by Andrew C. Erin.
Liz McAdams is haunted by the memories of a tornado
that destroyed her home 25 years ago.
Now a professional storm tracker, she and her family are in danger once
again as another devastating twister rapidly gains momentum.
Caught in the path of destruction, Liz and her estranged
husband struggle to save those they love...
Liz McAdams, played by Meredith Monroe.
Matt McAdams, played by Cameron Bancroft.
Ellie Wilson, played by Pascale Hutton.
Becky McAdams, played by Rachel Pattee.
Hank Wilson, played by Duncan Fraser.
Nora, played by Ashley Michaels.
This page documents notable tornadoes and tornado outbreaks worldwide in 2009.
Strong and destructive tornadoes form most frequently in the United States, Argentina, Brazil,
Bangladesh, and Eastern India, but can occur almost anywhere under the right conditions.
Tornadoes also develop occasionally in southern Canada during the Northern Hemisphere's summer and somewhat
regularly at other times of the year across Europe, Asia, Argentina, Australia and New Zealand.
Tornadic events are often accompanied by other forms of severe weather,
including strong thunderstorms, strong winds, and hail.
In the U.S., there were 1,304 reports of tornadoes received by the Storm
Prediction Center, and 1,159 tornadoes were confirmed to have taken place.
Worldwide, 73 fatalities were caused by tornadoes; 22 in the United States, 20 in India, 11 in Argentina, eight in
the Philippines, four each in Canada and Brazil, two in Greece and one each in Serbia and Russia.
Tornadic activity in 2009 began with the development an EF1 tornado near Stringer, Mississippi on January 3
and ended with the dissipation of an EF0 tornado near Vancleave, Mississippi on December 24.
During the year the two strongest tornadoes were both assessed as an EF4 – one occurred in
Oklahoma on February 10 and the second occurred in Tennessee on April 10.
During the early months of the year tornadic activity remained mostly below
average in contrast to an active trend of tornadoes in 2008.
Activity peaked in April and May as a result of destabilizing atmospheric
conditions and featured a bulk of the year's tornadoes.
However, the number of developing tornadoes subsequently began to wane and
remained generally inactive for the latter half of 2009.
The film explores themes of farm, tornado, widower, disaster movie.
The tone is intense and emotional and mind_bending.